# VOLODYMYR FORUSHCHENKO

C: 587.968.1394 | Calgary, AB

forusvy@gmail.com | My LinkedIn | My GitHub | My Portfolio

# FRONT-END JS WEB DEVELOPER

Highly organized and creative Front-End JS Web Developer with 2+ years of experience developing and maintaining different websites. Uses new trends in building websites, and monitors the updates of libraries and frameworks. Have a strong focus on writing clean, maintainable, and well-documented coding. With a great desire ready to constantly learn and acquire new skills, while always sharing his knowledge and experience with colleagues.

An excellent team player who always found compromises and is constructive and thoughtful in both simple and complex tasks. Extensive experience in a senior management position in a large telecommunications company interacting with individual and corporate clients in a rapidly changing, growth-oriented environment. Excellent at listening to customer needs and resolving issues promptly under tight deadlines.

CORE COMPETENCIES		
TECHNICAL SKILLS:		SOFT SKILLS:
• HTML5, CSS3	<ul> <li>Node.js, AJAX, Babel</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Time Management</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Flexbox, Grid, Animation, SCSS</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>React, Redux, TypeScript</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Conflict Resolution</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Bootstrap, Materialize, Tailwind</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Gulp, Webpack</li> </ul>	<ul><li>Learning &amp; Adaptability</li></ul>
<ul> <li>JavaScript, jQuery, VUE.js, VUEX</li> </ul>	JIRA, GitHub, GitLab	<ul> <li>Attention to detail</li> </ul>

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

MAR 2023 - PRESENT

### CITRUS (https://www.ctrs.com.ua/), ODESA, UKRAINE

"Citrus" is a highly visible and recognizable retail store in the Ukrainian market, which includes a network of more than 71 stores and an online store. The target audience of Citrus is active, advanced users of devices and gadgets: from headphones to laptops, from a quadcopter to electric bikes. Online store ctrs.com.ua is confidently among the leaders of online trade in Ukraine.

- Designed, directed, built, maintained, and performed updates on the main website and web application.
- Collaborated with in-house designers to redesign a website using HTML5, CSS3, and JS, making it responsive for mobile devices and increasing customer engagement by over 8%.
- Optimized code, cross-browser compatibility and web features, re-designs, seasonal updates, and production work with page load times under 2 seconds on a broadband connection and full accessibility compliance with W3C WAI-AA standards.

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER NOV 2021 – FEB 2023

# GEEKSFORLESS INC. (https://geeksforless.com/), MYKOLAYIV, UKRAINE

GFL is a Software Development, Staff Augmentation, and BPO company as an offshore IT services and staff augmentation provider for businesses seeking to extend their knowledge and team capacity while preserving control and improving costs and quality. GFL aim to provide world-class staff augmentation services of highly skilled and experienced technical talent to our customers as an extension of their technical teams.

- Effectively collaborated with designers, product managers, and back-end developers to deliver seamless user experiences, as evidenced by a team satisfaction rate of 95%.
- Designed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JS, and jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across desktops, tablets, and 20+ other devices.
- Optimized 30+ key content pages for SEO objectives, which improved online search-ranking accuracy by 63%.
- Built responsive websites from Figma/Photoshop for 20+ customers using HTML5, JS, React, and CSS compiles using webpack build tools.

Volodymyr Forushchenko – Resume

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER MAY 2021 – NOV 2021

#### FREELANCE UPWORK, KHERSON, UKRAINE

• Made layout of adaptive and cross-browser websites of varying complexity using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and JavaScript (30+ websites) with maintaining brand consistency throughout the design process.

- Evaluated code to ensure it meets industry standards, is valid, is properly structured, and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems. Achieved a +90% optimal website performance.
- Identified problems uncovered by customer feedback and testing, and corrected or referred problems to appropriate personnel for correction, improving customer engagement by 10%.
- Delivered engaging experience through optimization of images, code, and cross-browser compatibility. Increasing time on page by 60+ seconds for 20+ websites.

HEAD OF SOUTH REGION DEC 2011 – MAY 2021

# KYIVSTAR (https://kyivstar.ua/), KHERSON, UKRAINE

Kyivstar — is a Ukrainian telecom provider N $^{o}$ 1 and one of the greatest national brands, serving 24.4 million cell phone subscribers and more than 1,1 million Home Internet subscribers at the beginning of 2023.

- Managed own team of 11 full-time employees and 120+ contractor employees ensuring excellent sales, network uptime, upgrades, customer service, and timely problem resolution under constant deadline pressure.
- Invented and led the creation and development of a new stream of sales throughout the country, which in 1 year became a full-fledged separate sales channel and increased overall sales by more than 25%.
- Demonstrated excellent time management skills with no missed deadlines or requests for project extensions.

# **AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS**

Nominated in the top 50 best employees of the year out of more than 4,000 employees - KYIVSTAR Kherson, Ukraine

2020

### **EDUCATION**

IT Beetroot Academy, Front-End Development | Swedish-Ukrainian IT Academy

Master's Degree, Computer Systems and Networks | National Technical University, Ukraine

2021 2010

# **VOLUNTEERING & COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT**

Newcomer assistance | ST. VLADIMIR'S UKRAINIAN CHURCH, Calgary, Alberta

FEB 2023 - MAR 2023

Humanitarian aid to refugees affected by war | Kherson, Ukraine

FEB 2022 - MAR 2022

# **HOBBIES**

I am a professional soccer player, winner of the city championship. Soccer for me isn't just a sport – it's truly my life, my passion.